Beyond the horizon lies the secret to a new beginning.
Waterworld is a adventure, action, science fiction
film directed by Kevin Reynolds.
In a futuristic world where the polar ice caps have melted and made Earth a liquid planet, a
beautiful barmaid rescues a mutant seafarer from a floating island prison.
They escape, along with her young charge, Enola, and sail off aboard his ship.
But the trio soon becomes the target of a menacing pirate who covets
the map to 'Dryland'—which is tattooed on Enola's back.
Mariner, played by Kevin Costner.
Deacon, played by Dennis Hopper.
Helen, played by Jeanne Tripplehorn.
Enola, played by Tina Majorino.
Enforcer, played by R. D. Call.
Nord, played by Gerard Murphy.
Waterworld is a 1995 American post-apocalyptic action film, directed by
Kevin Reynolds and co-written by Peter Rader and David Twohy.
It was based on Rader's original 1986 screenplay and stars Kevin Costner,
who also produced it with Charles Gordon and John Davis.
It was distributed by Universal Pictures.
The setting of the film is in the distant future.
The polar ice caps have completely melted, and the sea level has risen
over 7,600 m (25,000 ft), covering nearly all of the land.
The plot of the film centers on a nameless antihero, "The Mariner"
(Costner), a drifter who sails the Earth in his trimaran.
The most expensive film ever made at the time, Waterworld was released to mixed reviews from critics, who praised the
futuristic setting and premise but criticized the execution, including the characterization and acting performances.
The film also was unable to recoup its massive budget at the box office despite being the ninth highest-grossing film
of 1995; however, the film did later become profitable owing to video and other post-cinema sales.
The film was nominated for an Academy Award in the
category Best Sound at the 68th Academy Awards.
The film's release was accompanied by a novelization, video games, and four themed attractions at Universal Studios
Hollywood, Universal Studios Singapore, Universal Studios Japan, and Universal Studios Beijing called WaterWorld.
The film explores themes of sailboat, human evolution, tattoo, ocean, mutant.
The tone is thought_provoking.